云幕 NAS电影服务器-家庭娱乐管家
本视频为演示影片，仅供交流，观影后请删除！
玩躲猫猫啦!
Peek-a-boo!
不玩了 不玩了
No, no, no, no, no.
不是故意吓到你的 小宝贝
I didn't mean to startle you, my little baby.
嘘 不哭了
Shh, shh, shh.
# 吸血鬼宝贝不说话 #
# Hush, little vampire, don't say a word #
# 爸爸为你咬下鸟脑袋 #
# Papa's gonna bite the head off a bird #
你这个调皮鬼!
A-bitty goo-bah!
来让我亲一个
I vant to kiss your tush.
让我亲下你的小虎牙!
I vant to kiss your tush!
不错 要是面积再大一点就更好了
Nice, but maybe a little more square footage.
我想要有很多的怪物住在这里
I want a lot of monsters here.
我来抓你啦 梅维丝
I'm gonna get you, little Mavis.
要抓到你啦! 哎哟
I'm gonna get you! Oy.
那外面是什么?
What out there?
哦 我们从不到外面去的
Oh, we never go out there.
永远都不
Ever.
"然后怪物们都四处逃窜 不得不躲避起来"
"And then the monsters ran away and were forced into hiding."
"但人类哈利还是找到了他们 并从他们的床底下跳出来"
"But Harry the Human found them and jumped out from under their bed."
- 我好害怕! - "烧掉了怪物的衣服
- I'm scared! - "And burned their clothes
啃掉了他们的脚趾头!"
and bit their toes!"
"还把他们的糖果拿走了!"
"And took their candy!"
不准抢我的糖果
Don't take my candy.
小宝贝 你不用这么害怕
Babyclaws, you don't need to be frightened.
我答应你妈妈会永远保护你的
I promised your mommy I would protect you forever.
# 我可爱的小梅梅 #
# My beautiful May-vay #
# 爸爸辛苦把你拉扯大 #
# Let me wipe all your poop away #
# 那些人类都很可恶 #
# Those humans are nas-tay #
# 爸爸会永远保护你 #
# So with Daddy you will stay #
# 如果有人类想伤害你 #
# And if a human tries to harm you #
# 我只会这样说... #
# I'll simply say... #
# 因为你是爸爸的小宝贝 #
# Because you're Daddy's girl #
# 爸爸的小宝贝 #
# Daddy's girl #
# 我是爱你的爸爸... #
# I'm your Vlad-y daddy... #
只要屈膝然后向前一跃
Just bend the legs and push off.
相信我 小老鼠
Trust me, mouse.
- 哈哈! - 我会飞了! 我会飞了!
- Ha-ha! - I can fly! I can fly!
快看!
Look at you!
用力飞 宝贝! 再用力飞!
Faster, baby! Faster!
- 喔! - 你做到了 我的小巫师娃娃!
- Whoo-hoo! - You got it, my little voodoo doll!
不好意思 先生
Excuse me, sir.
怎么了? 什么事?
What? What?
嗷 我没事
Ow. I'm okay.
都准备好了
It's ready.
看起来不错
Looks good.
只有怪物能进来吗?
Only monsters can get in?
哦 绝对没错
Oh, absolutely.
已经完美的隐藏好了
It's hidden real nicely.
在它前面有400英亩的亡魂森林
You got 400 acres of haunted forest in front of you.
周围全都是活死人墓地
You got the Land of the Undead on the perimeters.
任何走近此地的人类都会吓得逃之夭夭
Any humans daring to even look over there will run away real quick.
当然 放聪明点的话
But, of course, be smart.
不能有篝火 不能有烟火表演
No bonfires, no firework shows.
好吧 我知道了 不能有火光 我明白了
Yeah, yeah, no, no. No fire, I get it, I get it.
终于等到这一天了 亲爱的玛莎
It's time, my darling Martha.
这里就是我们一直想为梅维丝建造的地方
The place we always talked about for Mavis.
在这里永远不会有人伤害到她
No one will ever harm her here.
精灵旅馆
N年后
后车厢的行李就麻烦你了
Yeah, it's a mess back there.
欢迎来到精灵旅社!
Welcome to Hotel Transylvania!
1898年至今无人类出现
Human-free since 1898.
这里是你最安全的港湾
Your safest destination.
拿好你的旅行指南
Take an itinerary.
里面有我亲自为我女儿明天的生日宴会
I have personally designed a spectacular schedule of events,
设计的豪华活动安排
all leading to my daughter's birthday extravaganza tomorrow.
我们每年都盼望着来这里 伯爵
We always look forward to coming every year, Count.
我们非常享受这里的安全
We enjoy the safety so much.
那当然了 这里就是为此而建的
Of course. That's why we built it.
晚上好啊
Yes, good evening.
谢谢光临 玛蒂
Thank you, Marty.
你看起来还是那样苍白无力
You look pale, as well.
长官 有事禀报!
Sir, sir, sir!
我们发现一个紧急的管道问题
We have an urgent plumbing issue.
管道? 知道了
Plumbing? On it.
乌拉干先生!
Mr. Ghouligan!
348号房间的厕所发生堵塞
There is a clogged toilet in room 348.
没事的 每个人都会肚子疼 大脚先生
It's okay. We all get stomach aches, Mr. Bigfoot.
嘿 孩子们 别到处乱跑
Hey, kids, reel it in.
你们这是要爸爸妈妈难堪
You're only supposed to make Mom and Dad miserable.
好了 能不能乖一点啊?
Now, now, is that any way to behave?
这里可是旅馆 不是墓地哦
This is a hotel, not a cemetery.
抱歉 德库拉叔叔
Sorry, Uncle Drac.
德库拉! 你还好吗?
Drac! How are ya?
韦恩 我的老朋友!
Wayne, my old friend!
我们已经等不及这个周末了
Couldn't wait for this weekend.
好些日子想死了要出来透透气了
Always great to be out ofthe shadows for a couple days.
这一家子看起来真漂亮
The family looks beautiful.
让我来好好给他们清理一下
Let me just clean up their filth.
客房服务!
Housekeeping!
弗兰基 伙计! 看看你自己!
Frankie, my boy! Look at you!
还是和以前一样打包出行 吝啬先生 哈?
Still traveling by mail, Mr. Cheapo, huh?
这根本不是钱的问题
It's not a money thing.
我有飞机恐惧症 你知道吗?
I have a plane phobia, okay?
我的意思是 那些飞机引擎随时都可能...
I mean, at any moment, those engines could catch...
着火! 没说错吧
Fire! Yeah, yeah.
着火可不好
"Fire bad."
怪物都知道
We know.
奥古斯塔斯 粥点部长 给我放下!
Augustus, Porridge Head, come on!
那个看起来像是科学怪人的头吗?
Does that look like Frankenstein's head?
嘿 德库拉 兄弟 你的披肩是怎么回事?
Hey, Drac, buddy, what's going on with your cape there?
什么意思? 哦!
What do you mean? Oh!
谁在捏我?
Who pinched me?
抱歉 你太迷人了
Guilty. You're irresistible.
是啊 你嘴巴太甜了 隐形人
Yes, very amusing, Invisible Man.
你好 "见"到你很高兴
Hello. Great to "see" you.
还跟从前一样
Never gets old.
哈哈
Ho-ho-ho.
没打到哦
Missed me.
打不到 打不到 打不到哦
Missed me, missed me, missed me.
好吧 你赢了 拿着这条培根
Okay, you win. Hold this bacon.
我为什么要拿着培根... 啊!
Why am I holding bacon... Ahh!
不! 快下来!
No! Get 'em off!
派对达人来啦!
Here comes the party!
你好啊 默里!
Hello, Murray!
德库拉 你还好吗?
Drac, what's up, buddy?
沙子 默里 到处都是沙子!
The sand, Murray, the sand!
又是风尘仆仆而来
Always with the sand.
哟!
Whee!
小狼! 旺达! 还有弗兰克!
Wolfie! Wanda! Frank!
我爱死你了
I love this guy.
总是和我配合完美
He always bringing it full tilt.
你看起来还是那么瘦
You're looking skinny, too.
现在只剩一个头了
Now that you're just a head.
好吧 我会找你算账的
Okay, you'll pay for that.
到底怎么回事 德库拉?
So what's up, Drac?
看样子旅馆正在重整旗鼓
The hotel is looking off the hook.
嘿 伙计们 看看这个
Hey, guys, watch this.
顺便说一下 你的这些发展方向都是可行的
By the way, you were right about those directions.
哦 很好 不错
Oh, good, good.
我让底格里斯河(流经土耳其和伊拉克)与尼罗河通流
Yeah, I took the Tigris
这样就绝对无路可走了
through the Nile, and there was absolutely no traffic.
你这是在和我开玩笑
You're kidding me.
竟然在我的大厅放屁?
Right in my lobby?
德库拉 我发誓不是我 那不是我的放屁风格
Drac, I swear, man, I don't run like that.
客房服务!
Housekeeping!
那屁不是我放的
I was not the cause of that.
都准备好啦!
We're ready!
要是玛莎能看见就好了
If only Martha were here to see this.
她从未离开过 旺达
She's always here, Wanda.
好了 朋友们
Okay, friends,
很高兴各位能亲临派对现场
I am so glad you are here to celebrate.
我的宝贝女儿梅维丝一年一度的生日盛会
Another birthday for my sweet little Mavis,
同时又是成功躲避人类的新一年!
and another successful year of refuge from them!
这些都是我们监控器拍摄到的
These are recent human images
最新的人类图片
our surveillance has uncovered.
他们变得越来越胖 为的是能更加压制我们
They are getting fatter so as to overpower us.
他们穿的衣服也越来越少
And they are wearing less clothing,
他们就更方便勒死我们
allowing more movement to strangle us
把我们的头砍下来装糖果
or cut open our heads and put candy in them.
但是现在他们永远都不会
But they will never
在这里找到我们了
find us here.
邪恶的坏人 你们不会得逞的!
Evil villain, you will never win!
乡亲们 30分钟后开始狂欢
Okie doke. The fun starts in 30 minutes.
现在我要去看下我的宝贝女儿了
Right now, I have to see my little girl.
她不再是小姑娘啦!
She's not so little anymore!
不 她就是!
Yes, she is!
发生什么事了?
What's going on out there?
我们已经到旅馆了吗?
Are we at the hotel?
弗兰克 你给我们预定了双人按摩吗?
Frank, did you book us for a tandem massage?
你为我们准备好了一张驼背桌子吗?
Did you get us a table at Hunchback's?
该做的都做到了吗?
Did you do anything?
不用客气
You're welcome.
搞什么情况?
What's going on?
老爹 你说过的
Dad, you said that
当我118岁的时候 我就能像其他大人一样
when I turned 118 I could go out into the world
自由出入这间旅馆 到外面的世界看看
like every other adult that gets to come and go from this hotel.
"但是 梅梅 外面不安全 叽叽哇哇 叽哇叽哇"
"But, Mavey Wavey, it's not safe. Bleh, bleh-bleh."
老爹 30年前你答应过我的
Dad, 30 years ago, you promised.
我一直记得 当时我们在吃老鼠
I remember, we were both eating mice,
你很明确的说你会兑现你的诺言的
and you specifically said that you gave me your word.
请勿打扰
Do not disturb.
- 请勿打扰 - 请勿打扰
- Do not disturb. - Do not disturb.
请勿打扰
Do not disturb.
- 请勿打扰 - 请勿打扰
- Do not disturb. - Do not disturb.
- 请勿打扰 - 早上好 阁下大人
- Do not disturb. - Good morning, Your Eminence.
女佣 这间房需要打扫!
Maid, clean up this room!
你来啦 很高兴你能来
It's you. Glad you could make it.
- 她起来了吗? - 哦 起来了
- Is she up yet? - Oh, she's up.
她已经准备好出去了 出去看外面的世界
She's ready to go. And by "go," I mean go. As in, go check the world out.
你准备怎么做? 你准备怎么说?
What you gonna do? What you gonna say?
我已经安排好了 别紧张 做好本分的事
I got it covered. Please, relax. Just do your job.
早上好 梅梅!
Good morning, Mavey Wavey!
生日快乐 我的小老鼠!
Happy birthday, my little mouse!
谢谢你 老爹
Thank you, Dad.
我知道今天是我的生日
I know it's my birthday.
我为你安排了一大堆的娱乐活动 喔呵!
I have so much fun planned. Whoo-hoo!
但是 我们先一起去抓些蝎子
But first, we go catch some scorpions together,
就咱俩哦 怎么样?
just the two of us, yes, dead-ums?
老爹 等一下 让我说两句
Dad, please, let me speak.
有些事情我想和你谈谈
There's something we have to talk about.
你想去外面的世界 你可以去了
You want to go out into the world. You can.
啊!
Aha!
我就知道你会这样说
I knew you were gonna say that.
但是 老爹 你答应过我
But, Dad, you gave me your word,
而且你很清楚吸血鬼的话是神圣的
and you know that I know that a Dracula's word is sacred.
信任就是我们的...
That our trust is the core of our...
等下 你刚说什么?
Wait, what?
我说你可以去了
I said you can go.
你这是在耍我
You're just playing with me.
不是的 你已经到了能驾驶一辆灵车的年龄了
No, no, no, no. You're old enough to drive a hearse now,
你已经有能力做你自己的选择了
you're old enough to make your own choices.
你可以去了
You can go.
太棒了! 太棒啦!
Holy rabies! Holy rabies!
哇 等一下
Whoa, whoa. Stop.
稍微等一下 亲爱的小尖牙
Wait a second, sweet fangs.
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
哦 这个 我要去天堂
Oh, well, I'm going to paradise,
我觉得这些东西应该用得上
and this is just some stuff that I thought I would need.
- 天堂? - 是的 你懂的
- Paradise? - Yeah, you know.
就是你和妈妈相遇的地方
It's that place out there where you and Mom met.
旺达姨妈说
Auntie Wanda says you two
当时你俩一见钟情!
were just like, Zing!
我不知道什么"一见钟情"
I don't know from "Zing."
你在哪儿找到那张卡片的?
Where did you find that card?
在你的抽屉里
In one of your drawers.
你为什么从不告诉我你们是怎么相遇的呢?
Why won't you ever tell me about how you met?
其实那里是夏威夷
It's actually Hawaii.
夏什么夷?
Ha-what-what?
听着 亲爱的 我知道你很激动
Look, honey, I know you're excited,
但是现在所有人都是大老远跑来为你庆祝生日的
but everyone has gone to great lengths to come see you on your birthday.
我知道 他们每次都是
I know. They always do.
但我是不是已经不太适合参与这些活动了?
But aren't I getting a little old for these parties?
我爱他们 但是我真的很想接触些新的事物
I love them, but I really want to see new things.
或者认识一些年龄相仿的人
Maybe meet somebody my age.
好吧 不 别这样
Come on. No, no, don't do that.
不要可怜巴巴的样子
Don't give me the pouty bat face.
好吧 离墓地不远的地方
Okay, there is a human village
有一个人类的村子
just a little ways past the cemetery.
你可以去那里看看 然后差不多30分钟后就回来
You could go there and be back in, like, 30 minutes or so.
对于第一次出行30分钟已经足够了
It should be plenty for your first time.
好吧 虽然不是去什么夏威威
Well, it's not Ha-wee-wee, but I guess
但总算是能出去一回
it's still technically out there.
好了 好了 我知道了!
Okay, okay, okay!
非常感谢您这么相信我
Thanks for trusting me.
当然了 我的小乖乖
Of course, my little one.
我兑现了我的承诺
I gave you my word.
嘿 亲爱的!
Hey, honey!
- 看这里! - 嘿 各位
- Look at this! - Hey, guys.
你这是为明天的生日而兴奋吗?
You excited about tomorrow?
我现在有更兴奋的事
Not as excited as I am right now.
你们不会相信的 但是老爹终于允许我
You're not gonna believe this, but Dad is letting me
独自去外面看看人类的村子了!
go out on my own to see a human village!
- 什么? - 不会吧!
- What? - No!
请让一下 德库拉!
Excuse me. Drac!
你疯了吗?
Have you lost it?
你常对我们说外面的人类很恐怖
Letting your own daughter out there
但现在你却让你自己的女儿去冒险?
with those horrible humans you always tell us about?
你忘了建造旅馆的原因了吗
That's why you built this place.
人类讨厌我们 人类都是邪恶的
They hate us. They're vicious.
而且他们说话很吵闹!
And they're very loud!
尤妮斯姨妈 也许那些人类现在变了
Auntie Eunice, maybe they've changed.
我只是想飞到街上看看真实的现状
I'm just gonna fly down the street and see how it goes.
好吧 亲爱的 注意安全
Okay, honey, be safe.
多穿点别着凉 要带上魔剑
Bring warm clothes and a sword.
要小心干草叉子
And look out for pitchforks.
同样要小心不能让任何人把你的脑子铲出来
Don't you let anyone scoop your brains out, either.
也许待在阴暗处比较好
Maybe stay in the shadows.
在屋檐下静静的观察会更有趣的
It's more fun to just observe from under a house.
好了 伙计们 她能处理好一切的
Guys, guys. She can handle it.
看在上帝的份上 她可是一个吸血鬼
She's a Dracula, for Pete's sake.
但值得注意的是 小心火烛
But seriously, watch out for fire.
玩火者自焚
Fire bad.
再见了 各位
Bye, everyone.
喔啊!
Whoo-hoo!
德库拉 我不敢相信你能如此冷静地看着她离开
Drac, I can't believe how calm you are about her leaving.
真为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
德库拉? 你在哪儿?
Drac? Drac?
德库拉去哪儿了?
Where did Drac go?
喔啊!
Whoo-hoo!
太了不起了!
This is awesome!
这里有一个墓地 和老爹说的一样
There's the cemetery, just like Dad said.
喔啊!
Whoo-hoo!
呃... 有人吗?
Uh... Hello?
有人在吗?
Anybody out there?
- 吸血鬼 - 啃脚趾!
- Vampire. - Bite toes!
哦!
Oh!
嗨 各位
Hi, humans.
大家都好吗? 我叫梅维丝·德库拉 我是...
Everything okay? My name is Mavis Dracula, and I...
吸血鬼
Vampire.
- 烧掉衣服 - 要烧掉我的衣服?
- Burn clothes. - Burn my clothes?
- 真的吗? 呃... - 吸血鬼!
- Really? Um... - Vampire!
- 我们来拿你的糖果 - 糖果!
- We take your candy. - Candy!
我很友好的 真的
I'm friendly. I really am.
- 冷静点 - 糖果
- Calm down, now. - Candy.
我只是想跟大家打声招呼
I just wanted to say hi.
别这样 我从未伤害过任何人
Please. I've never hurt anyone.
我是一个宅女
I'm homeschooled.
那是蒜油味的吗?
Is that garlic?
我的乖乖 你们着火了
Holy rabies, you're on fire.
有什么需要帮忙的吗? 要我帮你们吗?
Can I do anything? Can I help you?
老爹说的没错
Dad was right.
成功了
It worked.
现在我的宝贝女儿永远都安全了
Now my baby will be safe forever.
好了 各位 都回去工作了
All right, everybody, get back to work now.
嘿 你不能把模特带走
Hey. You don't need a mannequin.
把模特放下 快点
Leave the mannequin here. Come on.
你去哪儿了?
Where you been?
为啥鬼鬼祟祟的到处跑?
Why you sneaking around?
嘘 闭嘴
Shh. Quiet.
宝贝 你这么快就回来了?
Sweetheart, have you returned so soon?
哦 进来吧 老爹
Oh. Come in, Dad.
感觉如何? 外面的世界怎么样?
How'd it go? How was the big world?
有没有什么新发现?
How was it out there?
还好啦 老爹
It was okay, Dad.
怎么了? 说说又何妨呢?
What? What's the matter?
老爹 你说的没错
Dad, you were right.
那些人类很可怕
Humans are awful.
和你说的完全一样
They were everything you said.
- 他们要啃我的脚趾 - 你的脚趾?
- They wanted to bite my toes. - Your toes?
他们还把大蒜汁浇在面包上
And they had garlic on bread.
什么? 看看我吧
What? Look at me.
我浑身都起鸡皮疙瘩了 吓死我了
I'm getting goose bumps, I'm so scared.
很抱歉 宝贝
I'm so sorry, sweetheart.
我难过让你看到事实
I hate that you had to see that.
很抱歉我不相信你的话
I'm so sorry I doubted you.
我再也不离开这里了
I'll never leave here again.
好了 没事了
Okay. Okay.
听着 老爹我将要为你举办一场最好的生日宴会
Look, Daddy's going to make you the bestest birthday ever.
看看我给你带什么来了
Look what I brought you.
你最爱的虫虫蛋糕
Your worm cakes.
不要再难过了
Don't be sad anymore.
还记得吧 今年我们将要打开妈妈给你留着的礼物
Remember, this is the year we open Mommy's present for you.
她给我准备什么了?
What did she get me?
拭目以待哦
We'll see.
她说了只有你到了118岁的时候才能打开
She said never to open until you're 118.
我们为此等了很久很久哦
We've waited this long.
先吃着你的虫虫蛋糕吧
You eat your worm cakes.
等你准备好了就下来 亲爱的
You come down whenever you're ready, honey.
- 啊 - 哦
- Phew. - Ooh.
你做了什么啊?
What did you do?
不得不做的事
What I had to.
嗯嗯
Mm-hmm.
她总有一天会感激我的
She'll thank me one day.
是的 这是把我头绑起来的那个人说的
Yeah, that's what the guy who shrunk my head said.
啊
Ahh.
你想要什么 饼干吗?
Yes, what do you want, a cookie?
你做的很好 老兄
You did all right, man.
继续向前走
Move on already.
啊!
Phew!
太好了
Yeah.
吸血鬼! 吸血鬼!
Vampire! Vampire!
一个人类
A human.
你是谁? 你是怎么找到这个地方的?
Who are you? And how did you find this place?
哦 我叫乔纳森
Oh, I'm Jonathan.
我只是和一群兄弟在爬山...
And I was just mountain climbing with some dudes...
然后听到一个关于幽魂森林的传说
and heard this story about a spooky forest.
任何人都想进入一个幽魂森林的 不是吗?
And who's not going to go into a spooky forest, right?
后来 我看到了那些着火的傻头傻脑的家伙
So, then I see these goofy-looking dudes on fire.
然后我就一路跟着他们来到了这里 一座不可思议的城堡
And I just kind of followed them to this, like, amazing castle.
当然了 放聪明点的话
But, of course, be smart.
不能有篝火 不能有烟火表演
No bonfires, no firework shows.
- 你们来了多少人? - 就我一个
- How many of you are there? - Just me.
我就是个独行侠
I like to hit it alone.
在青年旅舍可以碰到好多牛人
You meet so many awesome people in the youth hostels.
说道牛气 这件斗篷简直酷爆了
Hey, speaking of awesome, that cape thing is killing it.
这里是在开化妆舞会吗?
Is there, like, a costume party here?
我做了什么?
What have I done?
这都是我的错
This is all my fault.
你得走
You have to leave.
- 哦 糟糕 - 打扰您一下
- Oh, no. - Excuse me.
在你河里有条食人鲳太放肆了
One of your piranhas in the lake is very rude.
把我的小姨子给吞了
He ate my sister-in-law.
您稍等下
Be right with you.
德库拉先生 我们要看得到游泳池的房间
Mr. Dracula, we asked for a room with a view of the pool.
房间不错 我们想预约个按摩
The room's fine. We want to book a massage.
- 对 要瑞士式按摩 - 日式的
- Yes, Swedish. - Shiatsu.
- 要涂香料 - 还要照顾到下背
- Aromatherapy. - Lower back.
- 你们有热石按摩吗? - 我们来次按摩
- Do you have hot-stone? - We want a massage.
- 我去去就回 六头怪先生 - 但愿
- I'll get back to you, Mr. Hydraberg. - I hope so.
- 强烈怀疑 - 说话算话哦
- I doubt it. - See that you do.
- 是六头怪女士啦 - 谢谢了
- That's Ms. Hydraberg. - Thanks.
- 很高兴见到你 - 老哥 说真的 到底怎么了?
- Yes, nice to see you. - Dude, seriously, what's up?
这下面有股怪味
It's kind of funky to breathe under here.
德库拉 嘿 梅维丝怎么样了?
Drac. Hey, Drac. How'd it go with Mavey?
你要去哪?
Hey. Where'd you go?
哇!
Wow!
这城堡这么大 房间却有点小
This room's kind of small for a big castle.
没床 不过这里摆着的簸箕真是酷啊
No bed, but check out these awesome dustpans they give you.
安静 傻帽
Quiet, you fool.
你在这个包里藏了什么凶器?
What weapons are you keeping in this container?
干草叉子?
Your pitchforks?
哦!
Oh!
我喘不上气了
I can't breathe.
我要死了
It's killing me.
对啊 臭袜子能杀人啊
Yeah, definitely due for a fluff and fold.
这又是啥?
What is this?
刑具?
A torture device?
精神控制仪?
A secret mind controller?
休想窥看我的想法
You won't read my thoughts.
我不会让你得逞
l won't let you.
老哥 这就是用来听音乐的
Dude, it's just music.
来试试看嘛
Here, try it.
哦!
Ohh!
它摄走了我的灵魂
It's taking my soul!
啥? 这歌的节奏不错 开放点嘛
What? It's a good jam. Don't be a grandpa.
你得给我走
You need to go.
没有人类踏入过这座城堡 如果谁看到了你
No human has ever entered this castle. And if someone should see you,
城堡就危险了 没人会再到这来 没人会再把它当成避难所
the safety of the hotel, the sanctuary, no one would ever come again.
好耶 在说一次
Yeah, go for it.
"没人会再来！"
"Ever come again!"
我超爱你的德库拉腔 简直碉堡了
l love your Dracula voice. It's so over the top.
还有梅维丝 如果她看到了你 她就会发现我骗了她 不要啊!
And Mavis, if she saw you, she would know that I lied. No!
梅维丝是谁? 这是她的房间吗?
Who's Mavis? Is this her room?
多一个室友也没什么
I'm good with a roommate.
我家里有六个兄弟 分享对我来说完全没问题
l had six brothers growing up, so I could totally share.
我不能宰了他
I can't kill him.
这会让怪物的操行倒退好几年
It would set monsters back hundreds of years.
有次 我在汉堡和个老兄睡一间屋子
One time, in Hamburg, I roomed with this dude
结果我发现他偷我的洗发水
who I caught stealing my shampoo.
我叫了声"哇 没搞错吧" 然后他就朝我丢花瓶 不过他挺酷的
I said, "Whoa, man," and he threw a flower pot at me, but he was cool.
你唧唧歪歪的说什么?
What are you babbling about?
啥? 哇
What? Whoa.
看看这些酷炫的道具服
Check out these awesome costumes.
道具服
Costumes.
做什么呢? 对不起老兄 我没了背包可不行
What's this? Sorry, man. I just can't be without my backpack.
- 你知道的 我的家当都在里面呢 - 我们就把它放在这
- You know, everything I own's in there. - It'll be right here.
好啦 只是... 我爱自己的包
Okay, I just... I love my backpack.
哇 嘿 你干什么?
Whoa. Hey, what are you doing?
手往哪放呢... 你对我的头发做了什么?
What are you... What are you doing to my hair?
快住手 等下 好痒
Stop. Oh, wait, that tickles.
别玩了 老兄
Come on, man.
看我 我是个居家版的科学怪人
Check it out. I'm a Franken-homie.
- 对 好啊 - 看我这里!
- Yes, hello. - Look at me!
这完全正常 什么事情没有 我只不过带了个怪物
This is totally normal, not a problem here. This is just a monster with me.
老兄 今天大家都盛装打扮啊
Man, everybody stepped it up tonight.
等下 为什么往大门走? 我们要走了吗?
Wait, why are we going to the front door? Are we leaving?
你好啊 德库拉
Bonjour, Dracula!
嘿 长鼻子 什么事啊?
Hey, Sniffy. What's going on?
现在没空 卡西莫多
Not right now, Quasimodo.
什么?
What?
说什么傻话呢
No. Don't be absurd.
这不是人类 是德库拉先生
It's not a human, but Mr.Dracula
真是荒谬 是我啊
How ridiculous. It's me.
先生
Monsieur.
- 这是芥末蜥蜴指 - 芥末蜥蜴指?
- The devilled lizard fingers. - Devilled lizard fingers?
我要的是脾脏卷啊
I asked for spleens-in-blankets.
大白痴! 我告诉过你 他不喜欢
You ugly fool! I told you, he doesn't like
- 蜥蜴指头! - 但是你说...
- the lizard fingers! - But you said...
哇 看看那套打扮
Whoa. Check that costume out.
我得问问你 怎么才能出这种效果?
Wow. Seriously, I just have to ask you: How are you pulling this off?
我说 看起来好真啊
I mean, it looks so real.
就像是 可以把手伸进去...
Like, I could just put my hand right through...
你在干什么呢?
What do you think you're doing?
她是真的 你也是真的!
She's real. You're real!
没错 我的拳头也是真真的 离我老婆远点
Yeah, and I'll give you a real beating. Keep your hands out of my wife!
哦 惨了
Oh, no.
宝贝 我刚才不知道你去哪了
Honey, I just didn't know where you were.
我们以为你还在外面
We thought you were still out.
哦 我不知道自己为什么会想出门
Oh, no. I don't know why I eve rwanted to leave.
人类好无聊
The humans are so boring.
梅维丝宝贝 你没事吧?
Mavis, honey, are you all right?
我想没事 那感觉真怪
Yeah, I think so. That was weird.
头好疼啊
My head hurts.
- 嗯 那个人是谁? - 什么谁?
- Um, who is that? - Who is what?
哦 那个啊
Oh, that.
哪有什么人
That is nobody.
- 还没玩够呢 老爸? - "老爸"
- Seriously, Dad? - "Dad"?
对 我知道德库拉的闺女 大家第一次听说都会吓到
Yeah, I know, Dracula's daughter. Everyone freaks out at first.
还德库拉?
Dracula?
好吧 我们得走了
Okay, we got to go.
不要杀我 我还年少
Please don't kill me. I'm so young.
还有很多地方想见识
I have so many places I want to see.
我还要去戴夫·马休斯乐队的演唱会
I've got tickets to six Dave Matthews Band concerts.
我要从这里出去
I'm getting out of here.
给我闭嘴
Shut up already.
你吵成这样 我想不了问题
It's impossible for me to think with all your noise.
对不起 格林 回去睡吧
Sorry, Glen. Go back to sleep.
- 等等 你不吸我的血吗? - 典型的人类偏见
- Wait. Aren't you going to suck my blood? - Classic human paranoia.
人血脂肪太多 而且你还不知道那人都干过什么
Human blood is so fatty, and you never know where it's been.
所以德库拉不吸血?
So, Dracula doesn't drink blood?
我用其他东西代替血
No, I use a blood substitute.
血浆啊还有和血差不多的东西 都喝不出什么不同
Either Near Blood or Blood Beaters. You can't tell the difference.
所以 你就是 货真价实的德库拉
So, wow, you're, like, the real Count Dracula.
像是"我是德库拉 吧啦吧吧啦"
Like, "I'm Dracula. Bleh, bleh-bleh."
我活到现在还没说过一次"吧啦吧吧啦"
I've never said that in my life. "Bleh, bleh-bleh."
都不知道这说法哪里来的
I don't know where that comes from.
我能问问这到底是哪吗?
Can I just ask, what exactly is this place?
这里是哪?
What is this place?
这是我为了所有怪物建造的地方
It's a place I built for all those monsters out there,
他们在黑暗中游荡 躲避人类的迫害
lurking in the shadows, hiding from the persecution of humankind.
在这里 他们能和自己的家人一起回归自我
A place for them and their families to come to and be themselves.
这里没有火把 干草叉子 和愤怒的人群
A place void of torches, pitchforks, angry mobs.
只有平合和舒适
A place of peace, relaxation
还有宁静
and tranquility.
酷啊 所以这就是给怪物开的旅馆?
Cool. So, it's like a hotel for monsters?
对 没错 "给怪物开的旅馆" 总结的好
Yes, exactly. "A hotel for monsters." Way to sum it up.
好了 跳到我背上来 得走了
Okay, hop on my back. We're leaving.
哦 老兄 你变成蝙蝠了
Oh, man, you're a bat now.
我真的很想飞呢 感觉怎么样?
l always wanted to fly. What's it like?
这太疯狂了 等等 我不要走
This is insane. Wait. Wait, I want to stay.
能让科学怪人给我的衣服签名吗? 能让我见见隐形人吗?
Can Frankenstein sign my costume? Can I meet the lnvisible Man?
嘿 如果我把手伸到隐形人嘴里
Hey, if I stuck my hand in the lnvisible Man's mouth,
- 会怎么样? - 嗨
- would it disappear? - Hi.
梅梅! 你干什么来了 我的小血橙?
Mavey! What are you doing, my sweet little blood orange?
我们的朋友正要走呢
Our friend was just leaving.
对 他拉着我从窗户飞出来
Yeah, he was flying me out the window.
这家伙 他真是搞笑
This guy, he's so funny.
看那 你脸上沾了点东西
Look, you have something on your face.
想要再见到你的宝贝背包就好好配合
Play along if you ever want to see your precious backpack.
哇 等等 你在蝙蝠形态时没有衣服?
Whoa. So, wait, you didn't have any clothes on when you were a bat?
还是 它们就是蝙蝠形的?
Or were they bat-sized?
这到底是谁?
Who exactly is that?
嗯 我的小蝙蝠
Hmm. Honeybat.
你看 今天是你生日
You see, it's your birthday.
你知道 我想给你办场 人生最精彩最好的派对
And you know I want you to have the bestest, specialest party of your life.
嗯 所以我需要个帮手
So, well, I needed some help.
你需要帮手?
You needed help?
听着 我可能干了 但是我想
Well, look, I am very good, but I thought it would be
如果找个跟你差不多的人来帮我安排 那就会更特别 更好的
even more bestest, specialest if someone closer to your age helped plan the party.
- 你跟我差不多大? - 当然了
- You're my age? - Sure.
你多大?
Well, how old are you?
118岁
118.
一百...
One hundred and...
对 我121了
Yeah, I'm 121.
- 真的? - 对啊
- Really? - Mm-hmm.
看到没? 一切正常 超正常
You see? Everything is very, very normal.
我办派对 他来帮忙
I'm throwing a party, and he's helping.
- 先生 有紧急情况 - 现在没空
- Sir, there's an emergency. - Not now.
看不出来我们现在正在做一件超级正常的事吗?
Can't you see we're in the middle of something very normal here?
等等 出了什么事了?
Wait, what's going on here?
你的宝贝饭店里面有紧急情况 你却不去处理?
There's an emergency in your precious hotel, and you're not running to fix it?
为什么不去? 因为他?
Why? Is it because of him?
哇 看着我
Whoa, look at my face.
不是 心肝宝贝 不是因为他
No, precious bones, it's not because of him.
好啊 去看看有什么紧急情况 我来陪他
Good. Then go check on the emergency, and I'll keep him company.
- 不行! 这事绝对不行! - 什么?
- No! Anything but that! - What?
我是说 他得做计划呢
I mean, because he needs time to plan.
如果你陪着他 他就计划不了了
And if you're keeping him company, then he's not planning.
如果有人陪着他
He is company-keeping,
然后 计划 这... 计划就没人去计划了
and then the plan, it's... It doesn't get planned.
- 嗯 编的好 - 闭嘴!
- Mm-hmm. Good one. - Shut up!
好吧 等你之后不做计划了 我们就能一起打混了
Okay. So, maybe if you're not planning later, we can hang out.
- 听着挺好 - 对你听到了吗?
- Sounds good. - Yes. You hear that?
听起来不错
It sounds good.
你们等下再一起玩 再见了 小心肝 小宝贝
So you will hang out. See you later, my honey. Lovely.
好了 你们不能一起
Okay, you're not hanging out.
因为你要走了
Because you are leaving.
但是 你不是说
But the opposite, you said.
先生 还有紧急情况呢
But, sir, the emergency.
跟上来
Follow me.
娘诶 这小子好臭
Boy, that kid smelt.
我们这是去哪?
Where are we going?
从密道把你送走
Just getting rid of you
这样她就看不见我们了
through a secret tunnel so she does not see us.
我可以问你个问题吗?
So, can I ask you a question?
所以 你们怕洋葱是真的吗?
Is that real, about the garlic thing?
对 我不能吃 喉咙会肿
Yes, I cannot have it. My throat swells.
嗯 用木桩穿心你会死吗?
Huh. Wooden stake to the heart?
木桩穿心谁死不了啊?
Yeah, well, who wouldn't that kill?
好了 就是这里了
Ah. Here we go.
哦 对不起 我有点迷路了
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm a little lost.
我知道你们在度蜜月呢 对不起
Yes, I know it's your honeymoon. I apologize.
你们该干什么就继续把
Go back to doing what you were doing.
我不常下来这里
I'm not down here much.
这本来是人类入侵时 用来撤退的
It's meant to be an exit if humans ever invade.
所以 我是第一个来这里的人类? 这真酷
So, I'm, like, the first human here, huh? That's really cool.
哦 总算找到了
Oh, boy.
我想就是这儿了
I think this is it.
- 出什么事了? - 实在是抱歉
- What's happening? - I'm terribly sorry.
- 这是我的错 - 你们这些人有什么毛病啊?
- My mistake. - What is wrong with you people?
哦 老兄 这地方太棒了
Oh, man. This place is amazing.
好吧 让我耳根清净一会儿
Okay, I could really use some silence right now.
好的 坏事不过三...
All right, third time's a...
德库拉
Drac.
哦 弗兰基?
Yes, Frankie?
嘿 兄弟 你都在忙什么呢?
Hey, buddy, what you been doing?
别动
Don't move.
别管这个 你都在干嘛呢?
Never mind that. What you been doing?
我们想排练 为梅维丝的派对准备的大节目
We wanted to practice our big number for Mavis's party,
这些怂货就是不从台上下来
and then these losers wouldn't get off the bandstand.
把僵尸莫扎特放下
Okay. Put down Zombie Mozart,
还有巴赫和贝多芬 马上
Bach and Beethoven this instant.
你还用得着排练吗 僵尸贝多芬?
Did you get to rehearse at all, Zombie Beethoven?
听着 德库拉 我们想练一支曲子 像以前那样练
Listen, Drac, we wanted to play something, like old times.
我们还想你加入
We even thought maybe you'd sing with us.
算了把 老弟 你知道自从玛莎出事后我就不在公开场合唱歌了
Come on, fellas. You know that I haven't sung in public since Martha.
但是 我们只是觉得 梅维丝会期待你的表演
Yeah, but we just thought how much, you know, Mavis would love it.
我说了不要!
I said no!
别再问了!
Don't ask me again!
好了 现在和僵尸们抱一抱 大家言归与好
Okay. Now, let's hug the zombies. Let's all make up.
- 哇 他真的把你唬住了 - 才没有
- Wow. He really scared you. - I wasn't scared.
我只是有礼貌 好嘛?
I was being polite, okay?
嘿 你在这里干嘛呢? 我还以为你在做计划呢
Hey. What are you doing here? I thought you were planning.
我还不知道你的名字
I never caught your name.
我叫梅维丝
My name's Mavis.
梅维丝? 这名字真好听
Mavis? That's a pretty neat name.
对我妈妈取的
Yeah, my mom picked it.
所以 你要告诉你的名字吗?
So, are you going to tell me your name?
我? 我叫什么? 问得好
Me? My name? Good question.
明显 我叫科学怪人
Well, obviously, I'm Frankenstein.
你才不是 科学怪人是我舅舅 他就在那
No, you're not. Frankenstein is my uncle over there.
那个抱着僵尸莫扎特的先生
The gentleman hugging Zombie Mozart.
哦 对了 他当然是你舅舅了
Right. Of course, he's your uncle.
听着 我不是科学怪人本人
Well, see, I'm not "the" Frankenstein.
我是他的表亲科学约翰尼
I'm his cousin, Johnnystein.
- 科学约翰尼? - 嘿 梅维丝
- Johnnystein? - Hey, Mavis.
那是谁?
Who is that?
这些怪物要杀我吗?
Are these monsters going to kill me?
只要他们以为你是怪物 你就没事
Not as long as they think you're a monster.
嗯? 这有点种族歧视啊
Huh? That's kind of racist.
等下讨论
We'll talk later.
- 他是在拿我开涮吗? - 没有的事
- Is he making fun of me? - No, no.
他当然没有了 因为他是你的...
Of course he's not, because he's...
表亲 科学约翰尼
He's your cousin, Johnnystein.
对对对
Yes, yes, yes.
我哪来的表亲
I don't have no cousin.
不对 你有表亲 他是你的六代表亲 搬了三次家
No, no, you do. He's your sixth cousin, three times removed.
跟你的右手有血缘关系
On your right arm's side.
我的手有亲戚?
You have a cousin?
弗兰克 如果你的手能说话
Frank, if your arm could talk,
它就会告诉你 它本来的拥有者 有一个弟弟
he would tell you that the original owner of your arm had a brother.
跟一个女人结了婚
Who married a woman.
- 她嘛... - 掐死了一只猪
- Who was... - For strangling a pig.
我的手有亲戚掐死了只猪?
I have pig-strangling blood in my arm?
听着挺酷的
That's kind of cool.
好吧 表亲 很高兴见到你
Well, cuz, great to meet you.
你到这来干嘛 约翰尼?
So, what brings you here, Johnny?
- 哇! 那时什么? - 哦 对不起
- Wah! What was that? - Oh, sorry.
我该在说话前 提示性地咳一声
I should really clear my throat before I speak.
所以 你到底干什么来了?
Anyway, what brings you here?
来策划派对
Party planner.
对 我聘请了科学约翰尼先生来帮助我策划梅维丝的生日派对
Yes, I have recruited Mr. Stein here to help me with Mavis's birthday party.
等等 你请人来帮你?
Wait a minute, you asked someone to help you?
控制狂小队长?
Captain Control Freak?
是伯爵...
It's Count...
对 我想听听梅维丝同龄人的意见
And yes, I thought having a Mavis contemporary would be useful.
是的 他急需从新鲜的视角看问题
Yeah, he totally needed a fresher perspective.
好吧约翰尼 我们的木乃伊先生
Okay, Johnny, Mr. Tight Coffin over here
准备让这些涂脂抹粉的怂货在派对上演奏
was planning to have these powdered lame-os play at the party.
不过 怎么说 我觉得我们能把气氛炒热一些
So, anyways, we thought we could liven things up a bit.
哇! 你们都上场? 露两手让我们看看!
Whoa! You all play? Let's check you guys out!
# 姑娘哟 #
# Girl #
# 难以置信 你今天就要成年 #
# I can't believe it's your big night#
# 仿佛昨天 你还在吃着蚊子 #
# Seems like only yesterday you were eating mosquitoes #
# 但是现在 青蛙 老鼠 涂点 多力多滋 #
# But now you're eating frogs and mice #
# 你就吃的美滋滋 #
# Scarfing them down like Doritos
# 告诉我 #
# Tell me #
# 姑娘 时光消失到了那儿? #
# Where did the time go, girl? #
哇 哇 等等哥几个
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on, guys.
停下
Stop.
曲子不错 但是太校园民谣了
That's cute, but kind of old school.
是啊 说的好 约翰尼
Yes, thank you, Johnny.
节奏一定要快起来
You got to totally tempo things up.
来 我给你们示范
Here, let me show you.
狼人 给我起个调子!
Werewolf man, give me a jam!
二 三 四
Two, three, four!
# 牙齿尖尖的吸血鬼女孩 #
# Vampire girl with the fangy fangs #
# 刘海齐齐好可爱 #
# Hair real cute with the bangy bangs #
# 公主今天就要变女皇 #
# Little princess gonna be a queen #
# 蝙蝠美眉就要118 #
# Legal bat lady turning 118. #
- 118! - 说118!
- 118! - Say 118!
118岁
118.
耶! 来个台扑!
Yeah! Stage dive!
好棒
Awesome.
我现在真完全被征服了
I am so blown away right now.
我想我的表亲 一定能把这个
I think my cuz is gonna make this
办成最好的派对!
the best party ever!
对! 也许他还能帮我找几个妞来
Yeah! Maybe he can find a way to get me some chicks.
我们该办个跳舞比赛!
We should do a dance contest!
那些都没戏
We're not doing any of that.
我们得按照计划来 懂了吗?
We've got to stay on schedule, all right?
好啦 爸爸 好啦
All right, Dad, all right.
- 约翰尼 你也要来 - 我不知道
- Johnny, you're coming, too. - I don't know.
- 德库拉觉得可以吗? - 约翰尼 一起来嘛
- Is it cool with Dracula? - Johnny, come with us.
N-27号
N-27.
G-61号
G-61.
宾果! 宾果!
Bingo! Bingo!
你好大的胆子
How dare you.
你知道我是哪个博士造出来的吗?
Do you know what doctor made me?
不是我干的
I didn't do that.
自行车?
Circles?
苍蝇?
Fly?
- 手? - 电影
- Hands? - Film.
- 呕吐 - 叫呕吐的电影?
- Vomit. - The Vomit?
- 还是叫 吐出来 - 不是 这是无关的动作
- The Throw Up. - No. That wasn't a clue.
什么都没有?
Nothing?
- 空无一物? - 眼镜?
- Emptiness? - Glasses?
- 眼镜? - 摇摇晃晃的眼镜?
- Glasses? - Glasses shaking?
把眼镜摇到一边!
Glasses shaking sideways!
透过眼镜看世界?
Through The Looking-Glass?
我玩这个好烂
I stink at this.
跟我没关系
I didn't do that.
收回来 向上伸 再推
And pull it back. And up. And push.
转体 收回来
And twist. And back.
向上 转体
And up. And twist.
再推
And push.
别 这个不要学
No. Don't copy that.
收回来 向上伸 转体
And back. And up. And twist.
给我来个黑死病麋鹿鼻蛋卷
Let me get a bubonic moose nose omelet
配上蟑螂糊糊 还有老鼠果冻
with cockroach paste and mouse jelly.
再来点蛋白
And with egg whites.
你好啊 先生
Bonjour, Monsieur
要我给你做个蛋卷吗?
May I make you an omelet?
不 不用 我不饿
No, no, no, no. I'm not hungry.
什么? 埃斯梅拉达 你又闻到了?
What? Esmeralda, you smell it again?
- 是人味? - 我现在饿了
- Human? - I am hungry.
约翰尼 你去过泰姬陵吗?
Johnny, you've been to the Taj Mahal?
得了吧 没怪物去过那儿
Come on. No monster's been to the Taj.
天 我多想去一次
Man, I wish I could go there.
知道吗? 给我来50个蛋卷
You know what? I'll take 50 omelets.
你听到他的话了! 快去做!
You heard the man! Make them!
遇到强盗你怎么办?
How did you deal with the mobs?
是啊 夏天他们总是特别猖獗
Yeah, it does get pretty crazy in the summer.
不过也就跟着混呗
But, you know, you just got to roll.
就跟着混 真酷
He just rolls. That's cool that he rolls.
是啊 是啊 超酷
Yes, yes, cool.
看 宝贝 我带来了你最爱 会尖叫的芝士面包圈
Look, love droppings, I brought you a bagel with your favorite, scream cheese.
妈妈咪呀 太感谢了 老爸
Holy rabies. Thanks, Dad.
约翰尼 试试这个尖叫芝士 超级好吃
Johnny, try some scream cheese, it's awesome.
哦 真有趣
Oh, cool.
不过我不消化会尖叫的芝士 所以 不了谢谢
But I'm scream cheese intolerant. So, polite pass.
是啊 很明显嘛
Yes, of course you are.
约翰尼 和你商量一下派对的计划?
Johnny, can we party-plan talk for a minute?
你搞什么?
What are you doing?
让他们发现你是人类 小心把你打扁!
lf they find out you are human, they'll go bat poop!
放心吧 没人怀疑我
Relax. No one suspects anything.
如果他们觉得奇怪 也是因为你总偷偷摸摸的
The only thing that looks weird is how much whispering you're doing.
该结束了 说你要去游泳然后装得激动点
Just wrap it up. You will say you are going in the pool and act excited.
然后就说你拉伤了背要提前走
And then you will say you hurt your back and you have to leave.
大家嗨起来! 喔!
Here come good times! Whoo!
哦 兄弟们 哦 我的背
Oh, dudes. Oh, my back.
我要坐上来!
I'm on your back!
不 不是 他是说 "哦 我的背"
No, no. He said, "Oh, my back."
- 坐上来! - 来吧
- Get on my back! - Let's do it.
好 现在开始 水上斗鸡! 推到他们!
Aw, here we go. Chicken fight! Push them off!
水上斗鸡!
Chicken fight!
你不行的 约翰尼
We got you, Johnny.
等着落水吧
You're going down.
哦 是嘛 等着瞧吧 梅维丝
Oh, yeah, we'll see, "Mavey Wavey."
好了 大家冷静一点!
Okay, calm down with the fight chickens!
各位 别再闹了!
Everyone, stop the roughhousing!
喔!
Whoo!
弗兰克 如果你伤到了...
Frank, if you hurt yourself...
明白了 亲爱的
I got it, honey.
科学怪人家的男人就是为这而生的
The Stein boys are bred for this kind of thing.
高台跳水!
Geronimo!
咳咳咳
Eh-heh-heh.
孩子们 怎么能这么做?
Kids, why'd you do that?
我刚刚去游了泳
I was just in the pool.
水真凉啊
The water's cold.
不许笑我!
Don't judge me!
约翰尼 你的妆
Johnny. Your makeup.
你的妆啊!
Your makeup!
上来 快
Climb out. Now.
哦 天哪
Oh, man.
我猜伯爵也想游泳了
l guess the Count wanted to go for a swim.
水弹!
Cannonball!
哦 你可给我闯祸了 宝贝 你闯了大祸了
Oh, you messed up, baby. You messed up big time.
我告诉过你要低调
l told you to take it down.
如果他们发现 我的旅店就毁了
You'll ruin my hotel if they find out.
也许你只是嫉妒
Well, maybe you're just jealous
大家在这里终于能找点乐子了
that people are finally having fun at this place.
乐子? 那不叫乐子
Oh, that? That was not fun.
每个人乱七八糟地 又跑又跳又游泳
Everyone running, jumping, swimming with no order.
那一点也不像在找乐子
That was the opposite of fun.
你知道什么是乐子吗?
Do you even know what fun is?
乐子可是老子发明的!
l invented fun!
哎 就你也配长生不老
Boy, the wrong people get to be immortal.
看着我
Look at me.
忘掉我们曾经见面
You remember nothing of this encounter.
忘掉这个地方和你见过的怪物
You have no memory of this place or the monsters you met.
现在离开 永远别回来
Now go and never return.
等等 永远不能回旅店?
Wait, never return to the hotel?
哪尼? 你应该忘掉这个旅店的
What? You were supposed to forget the hotel.
我明明用超能力抹去了你的记忆
l just used my powers to erase your memory.
我盯着你的眼睛看的
l looked straight into your eyes.
呃 哦 可能是因为隐形眼镜
Huh. Oh, maybe it's the contact lenses.
- 隐形什么? - 这些小塑料做的便宜货
- The what? - These little plasticky doodads
能让我看清楚点
that help me see better.
等等 我把他们拿出来 很快
Here, let me just try and get them out real quick.
哦 这是我见过的最恶心的动作!
Oh, that is the most disgusting thing l've ever seen!
- 就好了 - 住手 拜托了 住手!
- Almost got it. - Stop doing that. Please stop doing that!
把手指从眼球上拿开! 够了!
Fingers away from the eyeballs! Enough!
听着 你永远都不能再回来
Listen to me. You are never to return here.
你要离这里远远的 也别把这里的事告诉人类
You are to stay away and never tell humans about this place.
不然我会找到你 吸干你
Or I will track you down and suck every ounce of blood
体内的每一滴血 直到你看起来像个泄气的坐垫!
from your body until you look like a deflated whoopee cushion!
去吧
Be gone.
竟然把我踢走 本来玩得挺好的
Can't believe I'm leaving, man. That could have been so great!
那家伙把一切都毁了 想吸我的血
Dude ruined everything. Suck my blood.
我应该说 "我就要留下 老头!"
I should have just said, "I'm staying, old man!"
像李小龙一样给他一脚 蹦! 对着他的...
Give him a Bruce Lee kick. Boom! Right in the...
哦 天哪 德库拉伯爵 别杀我 我这就走 这就走
Oh, my God. Count Dracula. Please don't kill me. I'm leaving, I'm leaving.
- 跟我来 - 哦 不 不 梅维丝 不行 我要走了
- Follow me. - Oh. No, no, Mavis, I can't. I have to leave.
- 真的? 很好玩哦 - 好吧
- You sure? It'll be fun. - Okay.
他不会发现我吧?
He's not gonna see me, is he?
哇
Whoa.
哇 看这上面的景色
Wow, would you look at the view from up here?
- 几乎可以看到布达佩斯(匈牙利首都) - 乌 达 佩斯?
- You could almost see Budapest. - Who-da-pest?
是在夏威威附近吗?
Is that near Ha-wi-fi?
啊? 哦 你是说夏威夷吧 是啊 那里超赞的
Huh? Oh, you mean Hawaii. Yeah, that place is a knockout.
我刚去那里参加了音乐节
l just went to a music festival there.
人类的音乐节?
A human music festival?
呃 我觉得是
Uh, I believe so.
那 他们会不会想咬断你的脚趾 还拼命塞给你大蒜面包?
So, did they all bite your toes and shove garlic bread in your face?
那倒没有 不过有个家伙
No. Well, one dude took a bigger bite
咬了我的能量棒一大口
out of my energy bar than I expected,
不过应该是太热的关系
but I blame that on the heat.
好神奇呀 你哪里都去过
It's amazing. You've been everywhere.
是啊 要不干什么?
Well, you know, what's the alternative?
呆在家里 足不出户 不知天下事?
Just staying at home, never exploring, never seeing what's out there?
一生只有一次121岁 对吧? 要活在当下
I'm only gonna be 121 once, right? Got to live it.
太对了
Yeah.
- 哦 天哪 这里看日出肯定很... - 喔
- Oh, man. The sunrise from here must be amaz... - Ow.
哦 对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
天哪 你是不是从来没见过日出?
Man, you've probably never even seen a sunrise, have you?
呃 没有 怎么?
No, not really. Why?
过来 我有办法了
Come on. I have an idea.
看
Watch.
- 啊 - 啊
- Ahh. - Ahh.
告诉过你们这里好玩吧? 是不是超级有趣?
Didn't I tell you guys we'd have fun in here? Is this not the best?
是啊 汗流浃背什么的是很有趣
Yeah, I'm working up a nice sweat.
那个约翰尼的啥时候才能安排好派对呀?
When's that Johnny kid gonna be done party planning?
- 超爱和他一起玩 - 是啊 他真够疯狂的
- He's a great hang. - Yeah, he's an animal.
现在梅维丝也对他青睐有加了 真好
And it was so nice seeing Mavis laughing and hitting it off with him.
谁青睐谁? 少来
Who's hitting what off? Please.
梅维丝才不会和他这种类型的在一起
Mavis could never be with someone of his kind.
什么? "他这种类型"?
I'm sorry? "His kind"?
你是说我们家的孩子不够好吗
You're saying our kind's not good enough for you,
"陛下"?
"Your Lordship"?
不 不 不! 弗兰克 我没...
No, no, no! Frank, I didn't...
我是说她不会喜欢头发又红又卷的类型
I meant that she wouldn't be into someone with such red, curly hair.
呃 又红又卷的头发怎么了?
Uh, what's wrong with red, curly hair?
你生什么气?
Why are you getting upset?
我的头发就是又红又卷的!
I have red curly hair!
鬼才知道你长了什么毛
Well, how was I supposed to know that?
这真是我见过的最美的景象
This is the most incredible thing l've ever seen.
约翰尼?
Johnny?
冷静 伙计们
Look, settle down, fellas.
还有啥意义呀 约翰尼已经走了
This is all a moot point because Johnny, he left.
等等 他走了?
Wait a minute. He left?
是啊 他说他不喜欢梅维丝 也不喜欢我们
Yes. He decided he didn't like Mavis, or any of us.
嗨
Hi.
呃 看来约翰尼改变主意了
Hmm. I guess Johnny had second thoughts.
你竟然还敢留下 你还是不懂
I can't believe you stuck around, man. You don't get it.
你的处境非常危险
Bad things are coming your way.
冷静 理清头绪
I got... I got to get my thoughts together.
好了
Okay.
看到这些桌子没?
You see these tables?
你用这一整天把他们推出来
You can spend the entire day pulling them out
然后摆摆整齐 派对策划
and placing them, party planner.
太棒了 我就困在这儿了
Fantastic. I'm trapped here.
我算是理解你女儿了
Now I know how your daughter feels.
够了! 够了! 停下来!
Enough! Enough! Stop!
站在墙角 休息一下!
Go to a corner, you're in a timeout!
休息? 我可是个成年人!
Timeout? I'm a grown man!
啊啊啊!
Ahh!
好 57号桌子 请到23号就位
Okay. Table 57, please move to position 23.
哇
Whoa.
- 酷毙了 - 面对墙壁
- That is cool. - Face the wall.
17到48 16到47 19到50
17 to 48. 16 to 47. 19 to 50.
- 额滴亲娘啊 - 给我安静点
- Awesomeness. - Just let me do my work.
29到35
29 to 35.
42到18 10到44
42 to 18. 10 to 44.
啊 17 18 19 20 21 22 23
17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23.
39到24
39 to 24.
36 起!
36 up!
29到35
29 to 35.
哇
Whoa!
31到19
31 to 19.
24 起!
24 up!
7到25 14到30
Seven to 25. 14 to 30.
哪去了 老大爷?
Where'd you go, grandpa?
别吓到了 重力小子
Don't freak out, gravity face.
等着认输吧 老尖牙!
Eat my dust, gray fangs!
56和43 到我身边来
56 and 43, to my side.
喔!
Whoo!
等着哭吧 小样
Prepare to cry, Billy Backpack.
咱就是这么酷! 极限飞桌啊 宝贝!
That's how we do it! Half-pipe, baby!
还不就那样
Whatever.
对 就这么闻
Yes. Keep smelling.
抓住人类 老子给你做人肉馅饼!
You catch the human, and then I will make human potpie!
27 45 65 76 48 挡住他
27, 45, 65, 76, 48, block his path.
挡住他!
Block his path!
哇哈!
Whoa-ho!
哦 别这么对我啊 伙计
Oh, come on now, dude man!
漂亮!
Nice!
哈哈! 哇哈哈!
Haha! Whoa-ho-ho!
接住你了 兄弟
I got you, buddy.
请勿打扰!
Do not disturb!
有人睡着呢!
People trying to sleep here!
看到了吗?
Did you see that?
那家伙是谁呀 霹雳侠吗?
Who is that guy, Sir Breaks-a-lot?
哦 天哪 我承认 真好玩 是吧?
Oh, boy, I have to say, that was fun. Okay?
你之前不是说乐子吗? 名不虚传!
The fun you were talking about earlier? Nailed it!
约翰尼?
Johnny?
卡西莫多!
Quasimodo!
梅维丝? 你怎么还不睡? 太阳出来了 会伤着你的 我的心肝
Mavis? Why are you still up? The sun is out. It could kill you, my honeyguts.
睡不着 知道约翰尼在哪吗?
l couldn't sleep. Do you know where Johnny went?
不知道 他...
I don't know. He...
- 你知道这干嘛? - 哦 呃...
- Why do you want to know? - Oh! Uh...
- 你喜欢他? - 什么?
- Do you like him? - What?
切 才不 拜托了 老爸 他又奇怪又笨
Pfft, no. Come on, Dad. He's so weird and awkward.
都不知道他是真笨还是太可爱?
It's like, are you an idiot or do you know you're adorable?
呃... 等等
Eh... Hold that.
- 知道卡西莫多的确切位置吗? - 是的 先生
- Do you have a location on Quasimodo? - Yes, sir.
他们正要穿过大厅 去往厨房
They're heading through the lobby, towards the kitchen.
让他们立刻停下来
I need them stopped immediately.
- 听清楚了没? - 非常清楚
- Is that clear? - Yes, quite.
我们马上去办
We are on it.
哈哈! 没打着!
Ha-ha! Missed!
你们这是干什么? 让我过去!
What is the meaning of this? Let me pass!
卡西莫多·威尔逊 跟我们走
Quasimodo Wilson, you are coming with us.
我咋会痛呢?
Why did that hurt me?
听着 宝贝 你才多大啊 还不懂爱情呢
Look, honey, there's no falling in love at your age.
妈妈当时就这么大啊 尤尼斯说妈妈先亲的你
Mom was my age. Eunice says Mom kissed you first
因为你不敢对她动手动脚
'cause you were too scared to make the first move.
是 是 是 是 是 是
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
别提我和你妈还有什么亲嘴了
Forget about me and Mom and kissing.
爸爸 总有一天 我会要结婚的
Dad, at some point, I'm going to get married.
- 我不能一辈子呆在这里 - 什么? 为啥不能?
- I can't be here forever. - What? Why not?
你还没脱牙套呢
You're barely out of your training fangs.
哈 哈!
Ha-ha!
我又赢了!
Quasi wins again!
一拳下去 屁屁着地!
When you bump with the hump, you land on your rump!
你怎么突然感兴趣了?
But why all the sudden interest?
每次我们谈到爱情 你总说
Every time we used to talk about love, it was always,
"哦 爸爸 真恶心耶"
"Ooh, Dad, that's gross,"
或者 "哦 爸爸 我不要知道这些啦"
and "Ooh, Dad, I don't want to know about that."
我也不知道
I don't know.
- 先生 他到厨房去了 - 他什么?
- Sir, he made it into the kitchen. - He what?
你是干什么吃的?
What do I pay you for?
对不起 宝贝 我要走了
I'm sorry, honey. I have to go.
我啥也没吃
He doesn't pay me.
在你杀我之前
Before you kill me,
能不能让我给背包留个遗言?
can I please talk to my backpack one more time?
我不想就这么丢下它
I don't want to leave anything unresolved.
你好 德库拉先生
Bonjour, Monsieur Dracula.
闭上你的臭嘴
Shut your hump hole.
你要帮他?
Now you are helping him?
你到底和这人类是啥关系?
What is it with you and this human?
他不是人类 他是科学怪人家的人!
He is not human. He's a Stein!
是啊 矮子 我是科学怪人家的
That's right, little man, I'm a Stein!
如果他是怪兽 让他吓吓埃斯梅拉达!
If he is a monster, let him scare Esmeralda!
那只老鼠?
The mouse?
切! 小意思
Pfft! Without a doubt.
好吧 看我的
Okay. Here we go.
呃啊!
Blargh!
呃哦!
Bleegh!
呃啊 呃哦 呃啊!
Blargy-bliggy-blargh!
人类! 是人类!
A human! A human!
先生把人类带进了...
Monsieur has brought a human into the...
埃斯梅拉达 帮帮我
Esmeralda, help me.
嘿 多谢你救我
Hey, thanks for saving me back there.
那家伙疯了 想吃掉我
That guy's crazy! Trying to eat me.
这事只发生过一次 在活结乐队的演唱会上有个怪蜀黍
That's only happened to me one other time. This weird dude at a Slipknot concert.
我要给你看样东西
There's something I need to show you.
喔
Wow.
嘿 我们在参加葬礼吗?
Hey, are we at a funeral right now?
哦 等等 不是 这是你的床
Oh, wait, no, it's your bed.
爽得让人脊梁发冷啊
So creepy and cool.
喔! 我知道她!
Wow! I know her!
我在爱之堡的废墟里见过这张照片 那是我最爱的城堡
l've seen that picture at the ruins of Lubov. That's my favorite castle.
据说那女人有一段传奇故事
There's a whole legend around that lady.
传奇故事?
A legend?
爱之女士
The Lady Lubov.
故事讲的是一个孤独的伯爵
The story is that a lonely count
偶遇了她 人们都说从未见过
met her by chance, and they say that no two souls
如此心心相印的两个人
were ever more meant for each other.
最后 他们安顿在爱之堡 也有了孩子
Eventually, they settled down at Castle Lubov and had a child.
不过后来 可怕的悲剧发生了
But then, a horrible tragedy happened.
那晚 一场神秘的大火烧死了他们
A fire started mysteriously one night, and it killed both of them.
当我走进城堡 仍能感受到他们摄人心魄的爱情
When I was at the castle, I could still feel their powerful love.
人们说 就好像有一个灵魂仍被困在他们的残骸当中
They say it's as if a soul is still trapped in the ruins themselves.
你的故事错了
The legend is wrong.
只有妻子死在大火里
It was only the wife that died.
哦
Oh.
她的死因一点也不神秘
And it was no mystery who killed her.
她是被你们人类烧死的!
She was killed by your kind!
吸血鬼!
Vampire!
- 亲爱的? - 去藏起来 我来处理
- Honey? - Go hide. I'll take care of this.
吸血鬼!
Vampire!
玛莎!
Martha!
他们才是真正的鬼怪
They are the real monsters.
我为了我的爱人 保护我的孩子建造这屋子
I built this place for my love, to protect her child.
身为人父 会为了保护家庭赴汤蹈火
As a father, you do everything to keep your family safe,
即便失去他们对你的信任也在所不辞
even if you have to break their trust.
可现在 梅维丝喜欢上了你
But now, Mavis has feelings for you.
什么?
What?
我... 我只是...
I... I just...
- 好极了 - 没事的
- Awesome. - It's all right.
你是个好人
You are a good one.
如果世界不一样了 也许你们还有可能
lf the world was different, maybe it would be possible.
德库拉 这都21世纪了
Drac, this is the 21st century.
人们已经和以前不一样了
People aren't the same as they were back then.
你确定 如果我们公开自己的身份
Can you tell me for certain that if we came out in the open,
每个人都会接纳我们?
everyone would accept us?
每个人?
Everyone?
好吧 你没说错
No. You're right.
这次我会永远不会回来了
I'll go for good this time.
你就说我有点急事
You can just say I had some emergency,
或者我被一个小精灵吃掉了之类的
or the gremlin lady ate me or something.
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no.
我不想搞砸她的生日派对
I don't want to ruin her birthday party.
你可以在结束了之后溜走
You can sneak out after it's all done.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不想伤害她
The last thing I wanted was to hurt her.
还有你
Or you.
其实 你扮科学怪人没有天分
You know, you're not the smoothest Frankenstein,
可你会是一个好吸血鬼
but you'd make a great vampire.
真的?
For real?
我就说我有一双催眠眼
'Cause I think I kind of got your hypno-eyes down.
哦 天哪 好吧 让我看看
Oh, boy, here we go. Let me see it.
小心! 因为你在我统治之下
Beware! For you are in my power.
我命令你成为狼人!
I command you to be the werewolf man!
我有好几个孩子呢
I have too many kids.
给我挠挠 我有虱子
Someone scratch me, I have fleas.
因为他是狼人 狼人有虱子
'Cause he's a wolf, he'd get those.
是啊 别 别解释
Yeah, no, don't explain it.
解释就不好玩了
It's not funny when you do that.
我又没订唤醒服务
I didn't order a wake-up call.
德库拉伯爵给每个房间都订了
Count Dracula arranged it for all the rooms.
那个打盹的按钮呢?
Where's the snooze button?
不能打盹 派对是今天
There will be no snoozing. The party's today.
哦 就这样 好极了
Ooh, yeah, perfecto.
118岁生日快乐——妈妈
# 姑娘哟 #
# Girl #
# 难以置信 你今天就要成年 #
# I can't believe it's your big night #
# 到吃青蛙的年纪 到疯狂派对的时间 #
# You ate your frogs, now the party's so right #
# 姑娘 时光消失到了哪儿 #
# Where did the time go, girl? #
# 姑娘 你曾经只能吸兔子的血 #
# And, girl, you used to suck a binky #
# 看看现在 #
# Look at you now #
# 你已能制服一整头牛 #
# You're sucking blood right out of the cow #
哇
Wow.
你真美
You look beautiful.
谢谢 谢谢你办的派对
Thanks. Thanks for the party.
是啊 喜欢我的小魔术吗?
Yeah, you like my little touches?
巴黎
纽约
莫斯科
夏威威
太神奇了
It's amazing.
- 派对真棒 - 你可真是超越了自己啊 德库拉
- Terrific party. - You really outdid yourself, Drac.
这是我500年来参加过的最好的派对
Got to be the best one l've been to in 500 years.
抱歉 巨人
Sorry, big man.
呃 梅维丝?
Uh, Mavis?
我现在超级害怕
I'm crazily scared right now.
可能这是件好事
Maybe that's a good thing.
你怎么能这样? 我还和你分享了我的痛苦?
How could you? After I shared my pain with you?
- 可 不是... - 爸爸 只是接吻而已啦
- But, no... - Dad, it was just a kiss.
不 你不可以接吻
No, you're not allowed to kiss.
爸爸 我可以做任何事 我不是38岁的孩子了
Dad, I'm allowed to do things. I'm not 38 anymore.
我可以喜欢别人 或者去看看外面的世界
I'm allowed to like people, or go see the world again.
什么? 你看到了! 你说你不喜欢那里!
What? You saw it! You said you didn't like it!
也许我想去村庄再试一次
Maybe I want to give the village another chance.
我只是需要学习 知道怎么随波逐流 就像约翰尼这样
l just need to learn, you know, just how to roll with it, like Johnny does.
不 不 你不能再去那个村庄了
No, no, you can't go to the village again.
也许你能让他们知道 我们可以做朋友呢
Maybe you can make them see that we could be friends.
不 那不可能
No, that isn't possible.
你凭什么这么肯定 只是看你怎么展示自己罢了
Well, you can't be sure. It's all in how you present yourself.
- 不 根本没用 - 你怎么知道?
- No, that won't make a difference! - How do you know?
- 就因为没用! -为什么?为什么没用?
- Because it just won't! - Why? Why won't it?
因为那村庄根本不存在!
Because that village doesn't really exist!
什么叫"不存在"?
What do you mean "doesn't exist"?
你做了什么?
What did you do?
我只是做了我必须做的事
l did what I had to do.
是什么?
What was it?
你到底做了什么? 告诉我!
What exactly did you have to do? Tell me!
我... 我建了那个小镇 那些人是我弄来的
I... I built the town. The staff put it all together.
僵尸们扮演了镇上的人
The zombies dressed up as the townspeople.
别生气 我...
Please. I...
如果你真的在外面遇到什么危险
If you really went out there and something happened to you,
我肯定不能原谅自己
I just couldn't live with myself.
但是你能原谅自己这样做? 对我说谎? 骗我?
But you can live with this? Lying to me? Tricking me?
尽管你知道我梦想着离开 但还是要把我永远留在这里
Keeping me here forever when you knew my dream was to go.
骗子! 骗子!
Liar! Liar!
是邋遢厨子?
Oil?
唔... 啊... 啊!
Uh... uh... uh!
请说英语
English, please.
你的声音太烦人了
Your voice is really annoying.
稍等 我来做翻译
Wait, I speak frozen.
他说 "德库拉把一个人类带进了旅馆"
He says, "Dracula has brought a human into the hotel."
- 一个人类? - 快过来 小甜心！
- A human? - Stay close, Pookie!
他说 "人类在辣里"
He says, "There is ze human."
他说话有法国腔
He has a French accent.
约翰尼不是人类 他是我右手那边的堂弟
Johnny's not a human. He's my right arm's cousin.
- 他在说谎 - 是啊
- He's lying. - Yeah.
而且他为什么在挖鼻孔?
And why is he picking his nose?
他说 "这就说来话长了"
He says, "It's a long story."
嘿 等下 别! 放开我!
Hey, wait, no! Get off me!
哎呦!
Ew!
他说 "看啊 辣就是人类"
He says, "Behold ze human."
真不敢相信
I don't believe it.
是真的吗? 你是人类吗?
Is it true? Are you a human?
是
Yes.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我不在乎 我还是想和你在一起
I don't care. I still want to be with you.
呃..
Uh...
还是算了吧 因为我并不想和你在一起
Well, tough. Because I don't want to be with you.
因为你是个怪物 而我讨厌怪物
Because you're a monster. And I hate monsters.
再见了
Goodbye.
请别伤害我!
Please don't hurt me!
这一切都怪你!
This is all your fault!
- 我们要离开这里 - 我再也不会来这里了
- We're getting out of here. - I'm never coming back here.
- 我早就觉得闻到了人类的味道 - "绝无人类"? 真是胡说
- I thought I smelt a human. - "Human-free"? What a rip.
哦 骗子伯爵来了
Oh. Here he comes. Count Crock-ula.
我真高兴我的眼睛瞎了 因为我可不想...
I'm just glad my eyes are stitched shut, because I don't even want to...
梅维丝 宝贝 你在里面吗?
Mavis, honey, are you in there?
梅维丝? 梅维丝你在哪?
Mavis? Mavis?
梅维丝 你去哪了?
Mavis, where are you?
梅维丝 你在哪?
Mavis?
爸 能帮我个忙吗?
Dad, can you do me a favor?
可以 当然可以 亲爱的 干什么都行
Yes, yes, of course, darling. Anything.
你能消除我的记忆吗?
Will you erase my mind?
不 不 这可不行 我不会那么做的
No, no, no, no. No, I won't do that.
有许多事情是我希望你记得的
There's too much I want you to remember.
你说得对 老爸 人类讨厌我们
You were right, Dad. The humans hate us.
宝贝 其实也有许多不错的怪物男孩
Sweetheart, there are so many eligible monsters out there.
你也还年轻...
You're so young to...
那是什么? 你在看什么?
What is it? What are you reading?
真爱 妈妈著
True Love by Mom
献给你的118岁生日
For your 118th birthday
"两只寂寞的蝙蝠 在黑夜里相遇
"Two lonely bats crashed in the night.
"他们怦然心动 一见钟情
"They felt a Zing. Love at first sight.
"那时起 他们便知道彼此将要结为夫妻
"They knew right then they would be husband and wife.
"因为一生中只会有一次心动
"For a Zing only happens once in your life.
"亲爱的 让你心动的人也会出现的
"Your Zing will come, my love.
"一定要珍惜"
"Cherish it.
"爱你的妈妈"
"Love, Mommy."
- 我觉得我们动心了 爸 - 你和约翰尼?
- I thought we Zinged, Dad. - You and Johnny?
我想只有我动心了
I guess it was only me.
不过你可以放心了 爸
But you should be happy, Dad.
我再也没有离开的理由了
There's no reason for me to leave.
也没有梦想了 我现在就和你一样
I have no more dreams. I'm just like you now.
天堂 你可以在夏威夷找到它
PARADISE you can find it all in Hawaii
玛莎 我做了什么
Martha, what have I done?
- 我的账单呢? - 在这呢 我是下一个
- Where is my bill? - Over here. I'm next.
- 我要退房 - 拿走我的钥匙! 给你!
- I'm checking out. - Take my key! Take my key!
这个迷你冰箱费用是怎么回事?
What is this minibar charge?
亲爱的 孩子们把迷你冰箱扔到了窗户外面
Honey, the kids threw the minibar out the window.
- 这难道是我们的错? - 这个...
- And that's our fault? - Well...
让一下! 不好意思
Excuse me! Pardon, yeah.
不好意思 有几个人需要快递
Excuse me, I got a couple of people to express mail.
朋友们 拜托了 停下来
Friends, please, stop.
太晚了 臭蝙蝠!
It's too late, rat-bat!
拜托 我求你们了
Please, I'm begging you.
我需要你们帮我找到约翰尼
I need you to help me find Johnny.
那个人类? 他可能会杀了我们!
The human? He could've killed us!
他摸过我的吉他!
He touched my guitar!
他把手伸进我嘴里 看它们会不会消失
He put his hand in my mouth to see if it would disappear.
他让我吃了他的滑板!
He let me eat his scooter!
我知道我说谎了
I know I lied.
我错了
I was wrong.
但是你们要相信
But you have to believe this:
约翰尼不是坏人
Johnny wasn't a bad guy.
事实上 我也不知道人类是不是依然邪恶
The truth is, I don't even know if humans are bad anymore.
弗兰克 别这样 老兄 你懂我的
Frank, come on, buddy. You understand.
他不会再跟你说话
He's not talking to you.
你先告诉我们人类都很坏 现在他们又变好了
First you tell us humans are bad, now they're good.
还有什么? 上就是下 冷就是热 精灵没有嗅觉
What else? Up is down, cold is hot, Gremlins don't smell.
嘿!
Hey!
我真的很喜欢约翰尼 不管他是不是我堂弟 他会讲好玩的故事
I really liked Johnny, cousin or no. He told fun stories.
我觉得他们一见钟情了
I think they Zinged.
他们一见钟情?
They Zinged?
但是我阻碍了他们
But I got in the way.
一生中只会动心一次
You only Zing once in your life.
- 喂 你现在短路了 - 我无所谓!
- Oy, now you're short-circuiting. - I don't care!
那我们还等什么? 去找约翰尼吧 来吧!
Well, what are we doing? Let's get Johnny. Come on!
- 是啊 就这么干 - 来啊!
- Yeah, let's do it! - Come on!
好啊!
Yeah!
我们应该在你父母家度蜜月的!
We should have honeymooned at your parents!
好吧 好吧 我要去哪里?
Okay, okay, where am I going?
人类世界 在约翰尼永远离开之前
The human world, before Johnny's gone forever.
那太阳怎么办?
But what about the sun?
我不知道 我大概得跟着混了
I don't know. I'll just have to roll.
他跟着混 他可以的
He just rolls. Rollability.
我们跟着他的脚印走
So we follow his boot-prints.
当它们消失的时候 你就派上用场了 韦恩
When they run out, that's where you come in, Wayne.
- 我? - 那里!
- Me? - There!
对 我就知道背包里一定会掉出来点东西
Yes, I knew something would fall out of that backpack.
嗷! 简直是恶臭!
Yowch! That stinks!
快用你的魔法
Work your magic.
等下 你想让我追寻这股气味?
Wait, you want me to track the smell?
不行 我的嗅觉跟踪功力早就不行了
No. My sniffing tracking days are way behind me.
你知道我换过多少块尿布吗?
Do you know how many diapers I've changed?
你知道那些便便早就毁了我的鼻子吗?
How many number twos have destroyed this thing?
不过...
But...
嘿! 别着急! 小心!
Hey! Take it easy! Watch it!
坐下
Sit.
闻一下 我让你们闻一下
Smell. I said smell.
不是我 是汗衫! 汗衫!
Not me, the shirt! The shirt!
你的孩子们当中还有谁听你的话吗?
Do any of your kids still respect you?
呃 稍等 哦 对了
Mm, give me a second. Oh, yeah.
维妮! 到前面来!
Winnie! Front and center!
他上了一辆车 是86年产的菲亚特
He got into a car. An 86 Fiat.
那辆车变速器需要修理 不过不修也没事
It needs a little transmission work, but otherwise okay.
它开向城里的机场 497号航班
It drove through town to the airport. Flight 497.
上午八点起飞
8:00 a.m. departure.
还有15分钟
That's in 15 minutes.
座位号是23A
Seat 23A.
他订了素食餐点
He ordered the vegetarian meal.
好的 谢谢你 小可爱
Okay, thank you, cutie.
现在 你们全都回到妈妈身边!
Now, all of you, go back to your mother!
有只羊!
Sheep!
太棒了! 别让我在外面挂着
High five! Don't leave me hanging.
- 好多羊! - 我来解决它们
- Lots of sheep! - I got this one.
怎么了? 现在路上没有羊了 走吧
What? Now there's no sheep in the road. Let's go.
这有点恶心 老兄
That was pretty sick, man.
你也吃羊排 没什么区别
You eat lamb chops, it's the same thing.
我们没时间说这个了 快点 开车!
We don't have time for this. Come on, let's move it!
看 有个人!
Look, a human.
欢迎来到精灵旅社！
Welcome to Transylvania!
我有点晕了
That was trippy.
怪物节?
Monster Festival?
什么是怪物节?
What's a Monster Festival?
我们爱德库拉
We love Dracula
我为科学怪人举火把
I carry a torch for Frankenstein
他们早知道我们要来?
Did they know we were coming?
他们喜欢我们?
They like us?
真的?
Really?
打扰一下 你知道去机场最快的路线吗?
Excuse me? Do you know the best way to the airport?
知道 德库拉老兄 只有那一条路 哇啊啊
Yes, fellow Dracula. There's only one way. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
但是路被堵住了 我们不可能及时赶到的
But it's all blocked. We'll never make it in time.
你应该提前一小时出来的 哇啊啊
You should have left an hour earlier. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
我从来不说"哇啊啊"
I do not say "Bleh, bleh-bleh."
好吧 我们跑过去吧
All right, let's just run through it on foot.
德库拉 这个会保护你的
Drac, this'll protect you.
哇啊啊
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
想象一下 如果那个人知道他是在和真的德库拉说话
Imagine if that guy knew he was talking to the real Drac,
他会吓的跑得远远的!
he'd run for the hills!
等一下 等一下
Hold it, now. Hold it, now.
这可说到点上了
That sounds spot on.
不过只有我们展示出来我们是真的 他们才会知道
But the only way they'd know the real us is if we show the real us.
这个办法不错
This could work.
你是说 比如 吓唬他们? 我们都有几个世纪没吓唬过人类了
You mean, like, scare them? We haven't scared people in centuries.
我甚至都不觉得我还知道怎么吓唬人
I don't even think I have it in me anymore.
我不会了 我真的什么都不会了
I got nothing. I really got nothing.
只要划一下火柴就好了
Let's just move this along.
火! 火!
Fire! Fire!
火!
Fire!
我在吓唬你们!
I'm trying to scare you!
我是真正的科学怪人！
The real Frankenstein!
我们知道! 我们爱你!
We know! We love you!
你能在我的火把上签个名吗?
Can you sign my torch?
听着 说正事之前 我先告诉大家那位是真正的德库拉!
Listen, before anything else, down there's the real Dracula!
能证明吗?
Prove it.
好吧 继续
All right. Continue.
德库拉的女儿坠入爱河了 而他需要赶到机场!
Drac's daughter's in love, and he's got to get to the airport!
但他没法穿过人海!
And he can't get through this crowd!
- 他为什么不飞过去? - 因为太阳 你个笨蛋 他是吸血鬼
- Why doesn't he fly? - The sun, you idiot. He's a vampire.
说得好 谢谢你 书呆子怪物
That's right. Thank you, Monster Nerd.
那么 如果你们真的是我们的朋友 请为他让出一条路来!
So, people, if you really are our friends, clear a path for the man!
好吧 所有吸血鬼 列队 哇啊啊
Okay. All Draculas, line up. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
其他人拉起斗篷 保护我们的朋友 哇啊啊
Everyone else, lift the capes. Protect our friend. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
这都是为了你 老兄
It's all for you, buddy.
去吧
Go ahead.
- 祝你好运! - 去找到他们!
- Good luck! - Go get them!
快 德库拉 快!
Go, Drac, go!
- 去吧 德库拉! - 快 德库拉!
- Go, Drac! - Go, Drac!
加油 德库拉!
Go, Drac!
快点 德库拉!
去吧 德库拉!
Go, Drac!
去找他们吧!
Go get them!
快点 德库拉!
Go, Drac, go!
我们爱你 德库拉!
We love you, Dracula!
别无选择了
There's no choice.
嗷 嗷 嗷 嗷
Ouch. Ouch, ouch, ouch.
好吧 我必须这么做
Okay. Okay, I must do this.
约翰尼 约翰尼 你能听见我说话吗?
Jonathan. Jonathan, can you hear me?
告诉我 你想变成吸血鬼吗?
Tell me, do you dream of being a vampire?
他们就是这样描写我们的 难以置信
This is how we're represented. Unbelievable.
嘿 约翰尼
Jonathan. Jonathan.
你能听见吗?
Can you hear me?
哇! 蝙蝠!
Whoa! Bat!
等下 它在说话 德库拉? 是你吗?
Wait, it's talking. Dracula? Is that you?
什么? 德库拉
Huh? Dracula.
我听不见你说话
I can't understand you.
什么? 棕色皮鞋里有我的爪子?
What? My hand's in a tan shoe?
什么? 日本在吃炖羊扒?
What? Japan's eating lamb stew?
嘿 你知道你在冒烟吗?
Hey, do you know you're smoking?
哦
Oh.
对不起 不好意思
Pardon me. Sorry, excuse me.
啊 对不起
Whoa! Excuse me.
- 这是什么鬼东西? - 蝙蝠怎么能飞这么高?
- What the heck? - How'd a bat get up this high?
乘客朋友们 我将点亮安全带指示灯 只是为了防止在我们...
Folks, I'm gonna turn on the seat belt sign. Just a precaution while we...
听到一段特别声明的过程中出现意外 这是为我的朋友约翰尼准备的
While we hear a special announcement for my dear friend Jonathan.
是德库拉?
Dracula?
我亲爱的的孩子 我犯了严重的错误
My dear boy, I have made a terrible mistake.
我试着让我的宝贝女儿呆在我身边
I was trying to keep my baby to myself,
因为我以为 我可以一直保护她
because I knew I would always protect her.
但我现在意识到 孩子们需要自己去探索
But I realize now, children need to discover things for themselves.
他们会跌倒 会摔跤 这过程中有笑有泪
They'll stumble and fall, laugh and cry,
但这就是生活
but such is life.
事实上 你和梅维丝是天生一对
The truth is, you and Mavis are meant to be.
你们一见钟情
You Zinged.
如果她除了我之外必须信任另外的人
If she must give her trust to someone else,
那我很高兴那人是你 约翰尼
I'm thankful that it is you, Jonathan.
我希望你能听见我说话并且原谅我
I hope you can hear me and forgive me.
好了 乘客朋友们 我们将马上调头回去加油
Okay, folks, we're going to make a quick turnaround to refuel,
之后我们将正常航行
and then we'll be back on our way.
别抱怨了! 我身上都着火了!
Quit your whining! I'm burning up out here!
爸?
Dad?
我没事 有点晒伤而已
I'm fine. I'm just a little sunburnt.
亲爱的
Honey,
我一直以为最糟糕的是就是看着你离开
I always thought the worst thing ever would be seeing you go.
但是最糟的是看见你不开心
But the worst is seeing you unhappy.
梅维丝 我想让你拥有属于自己的生活
Mavey, I want you to live your life.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know how I'm supposed to do that.
你知道的 你妈妈已经送给你生日礼物了
You know, Mommy already gave you her birthday present.
现在给你我的礼物好吗?
Can I now give you mine?
我要这个有什么用?
What do I need this for?
哦 它还有个配件
Oh, it comes with an accessory.
- 是你? - 是你
- You? - You.
你怎么回来了?
Why are you back?
因为你是我的梦中情人 梅维丝
Because you're my Zing, Mavis.
我是你的梦中情人?
I'm your Zing?
但是你说你讨厌怪物
But you told me you hate monsters.
是 因为当时我害怕如果我不那么说
Yeah, well, I was afraid your dad was gonna
你爸爸就会吸干我的血
suck all the blood out of my body if I didn't say that.
我才不会...
I wouldn't have...
不 他说得对 我会那么干的
No, he's right, I would have done that.
- 爸 - 我错了 我认定他们都很坏
- Dad. - I was wrong, Devil-chops.
你真的同意 老爸?
Do you really mean it, Dad?
去创造你们自己的天堂吧
Go make your own paradise.
我可以试着重新亲你一次吗?
Can we try that kiss over again?
我想可以
I think we can.
对不起 我只是... 我得学着习惯这个
Sorry. I just... I got to get used to that.
继续 做你们的事吧
Go. Do your thing.
祝梅维丝生日快乐
Happy Birthday Mavis
停! 停!
Stop! Stop!
# 我以为我找到了真爱 但那只是幻影 #
# I thought I found a love but she was just a fling #
# 后来遇到一个女孩 我发现不同的事情 #
# And then I met a girl and felt a different thing #
# 就好像是被击中 被绳子拽着前行 #
# It's like you're hit in the ring Like you're pulled by a string #
# 我无法呼吸 就像骨头卡住脖颈 #
# Can't breathe like you're choking on a chicken wing #
# 这感觉是一见钟情 让我唱给你听 #
# It was a thing called a Zing and I wanted to sing #
# 一起聆听那首小调 它来自斯汀 #
# And listen to ballads of the man named Sting #
# 看着你的眼睛 就好像是春天已经来临 #
# Lady looks in your eyes and it's suddenly spring #
# 就像狮子王里 当娜娜看着辛巴的眼睛 #
# Like when Nala looked at Simba in The Lion King #
# 我竟然没察觉到爱情的来临 #
# Zinging in the air and I don't have a care #
# 自由翱翔在我们的爱情中 #
# I'm winging from the Zing that we shared #
# 在雨中相爱 没有丝毫伤痛 #
# Zinging in the rain now I'm feeling no pain #
# 让我们一起庆祝这一刻 #
# It's a real time for celebrating #
# 因为我们的爱是命中注定 #
# Because you're my Zing #
德库拉 你准备来下面加入我们吗?
Drac, you ready to throw down?
不 不 我来前面只是想听得更清楚
No, no, I just came closer to hear you better.
来吧 试一下
Come on, just give it a try.
好吧 试一下也行
All right, maybe just a little.
# 不管朋友你来自哪里 都一定要听清 #
# So listen all you Zingers from here to Beijing #
# 你最好跳下蹦床 站稳扶好别太吃惊 #
# You better crash the box spring get ready to cling #
# 假如爱情即金钱 你们会往银行跑不停 #
# Because if love was money you'd be yelling cha-ching #
# 丘比特的爱神之箭 也会让人有点疼 #
# Next to a Zing Cupid's arrow's a little bee sting #
# 这感觉就叫做 就叫做一见钟情 #
# It was a Zing and a zang and a zingidy-dee #
# 这世上让我动心的 只有她一个女生 #
# And there was only one lady in the Zing for me #
# 因为当你遇到爱 #
# Because when you're dinged by the Zing #
# 你要懂得一件事情 你将要拿起的闪亮首饰 #
# You better know one thing the only bling you gonna sling #
# 是一枚戒指 #
# Is a wedding ring #
# 爱情已经来临 #
# Zinging in the air #
# 让我不顾一切 #
# Now I don't have a care #
# 在我们的爱中自由翱翔 #
# I'm winging from the Zing that we shared #
# 相爱在雨中 没有丝毫伤痛 #
# Zinging in the rain now I'm feeling no pain #
# 让我们来庆祝此刻 #
# It's a real time for celebrating #
# 因为我们的爱是命中注定 #
# Because you're my Zing #
# 所有的人 感觉到爱 #
# Feel the Zing, y'all Ba-da-bing, y'all #
# 那枚戒指 让你震惊 #
# Gonna knock you right out of that ring, y'all #
# 你们最好带上它 好事要发生 #
# Better bring, y'all happening, y'all #
# 你们都要注意看我这个不死之王 #
# Pay attention to the undead king, y'all #
# 我是怪物 我是怪怪物 #
# I'm a monster I'm a m-monster #
客房服务!
Housekeeping!
# 我独一无二 大家都喜欢 #
# I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love #
# 我不用强求 只是随心所欲 #
# And I don't have to try, I just do what I does #
# 不要告诉我 我已经明白 #
# Don't have to tell me, I already know #
# 大家都把我来爱 #
# They all want me #
# 呦 我经营它 又打破它 #
# Yo, I run this, I smash it #
# 就像我的贝斯一样坚强到爆炸 #
# Like my bass real hard, boom-bastic #
# 和我赛跑 宝贝 我能更快 #
# Speed race, baby, I'm a lot faster #
# 爱惹麻烦 从来不听 老板的话 #
# Cause trouble, never listen to my master #
# 新的奔驰 黑色那辆 来自马来西亚 #
# New Benz all black from Malaysia #
# 我不能看车 不过我妈妈不在乎啊 耶 #
# Can't drive, but my mama don't care, yup #
# 一路向上 我到了房顶 #
# To the top, I'm take it to the ceiling #
# 站在月亮上 但我怕太阳 #
# I'm on the moon but I feel the sun beaming #
# 我过于兴奋 想跳草裙舞 飞起来就好像 直升机降临 #
# I'm so dope like ooh la la so, so fly like a helicopter #
# 让流浪人吃饭 他的同乡来堵住街道 我无法前行 #
# Sup to the hood and the homies on the block #
# 把事情做大 耶 这你懂的 怎么了 #
# Doing it big, yeah, you know, what's up #
# 有人来这说我是个麻烦 #
# Some come and try to say I'm a problem #
# 太疯狂了 他们都应该去疯人院 #
# So crazy, gotta put them in an asylum #
# 有人来这说我是个麻烦 #
# Some come and try to say I'm a problem #
# 哈 解决掉他 #
# Ha, solve it #
# 我是怪物 我是怪怪物 #
# I'm a monster, I'm a m-monster #
# 我独一无二 大家都喜欢 #
# I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love #
# 我不用强求 只随心所欲 #
# And I don't have to try, I just do what I does #
# 不用告诉我 我已经明白 #
# Don't have to tell me, I already know #
# 大家都把我来爱 #
# They all want me #
# 呦 呦 呦 #
# Yo, yo, yo #
# 我经营它 我唱摇滚 #
# I ran this, I rock this #
# 我看得到未来 我别无选择 #
# I can see the future, no optics #
# 还有更多机器人 机器人 #
# More androids, robotics #
# 让美女围在我身边 就好像我是斯波克 #
# Beam up hot chicks like I'm Spock #
# 他们在我的座舱里兴奋得发抖 我的飞船有异域来客 #
# They be chilling in my cockpit my spaceship got exotic #
# 有个人被绊倒 她过来打我 我就把她催眠了 #
# One be tripping, come and whip, hypnotic #
# 她们会聊关于草裙舞的事情 #
# They be talking 'bout ooh la la #
# 让我们远行 超越群星 #
# Let's go far, way past them stars #
# 我们从不放弃 我们去火星 #
# We don't give up let's go to Mars #
# 啊 呦 我只是想让这成为潮流 #
# Ay, yo I'm just trying to get it popping #
# 我想成为第一个爱上火星美女的人 #
# I wanna be the first dude to love a Martian #
# 她若需要一个人帮她去拎包 那么我愿效劳 #
# She'll have a maid for the swag that I'm dropping #
# 我能杀死猎物 让它在棺材里颤抖 #
# I kill the game til it's chilling in the coffin #
# 我一旦开始 就不会轻易停手 #
# When I start, there ain't no stopping #
# 别装作 装作什么都不知道 #
# Don't be acting like Like you didn't know #
# 就像你不知道 就像你不知道 #
# Like you didn't know Like you didn't know #
# 就像你不知道 #
# Like you didn't know #
# 我独一无二 大家都喜欢 #
# I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love #
# 我不用强求 只是随心所欲 #
# And I don't have to try, I just do what I does #
# 不用告诉我 我已经明白 #
# Don't have to tell me, I already know #
# 大家都把我来爱 #
# They all want me #
# 我独一无二 大家都喜欢 #
# I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love #
# 我不用强求 我只是随心所欲 #
# And I don't have to try, I just do what I does #
# 不用告诉我 我已经明白 #
# Don't have to tell me, I already know #
# 大家都把我来爱 #
# They all want me #
# 我是怪物 我是怪... #
# I'm a monster, I'm a... #
我什么都没干
I didn't do that.